<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsBlock>
	<ModSettings Class="ShitRimWorldSays.Settings">
		<database>
			<quotes>
				<li>
					<author>ripmorld</author>
					<body>It isn't human it's "synthetic" meat. - McDonald's manager</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/hsvm1t/it_isnt_human_its_synthetic_meat_mcdonalds_manager/</permalink>
					<score>203</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>KoubuKai</author>
					<body>"Well, we've learned how to gruesomely profane the sanctity of the human mind by butchering someone like an animal, so that we may feed this abomination of silicon and sentience."

"Sure have. Now then, would you fancy a spot of cheese?"

"Why, I thought you'd never ask."</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hrbus6/my_colony_really_does_have_its_priorities_in_order/fy3gb55/</permalink>
					<score>248</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>MentalMallard28</author>
					<body>I can’t believe that some people let their prisoners have the mercy of death. I stick mine on life support, blow their brains out, and use them as a spigot for blood, which I use in place of medicine for autopsies. Harvesting organs while their alive is such a pain, it’s much easier when the flesh scan isn’t screaming and thrashing.</body>
					<permalink>/r/SpaceCannibalism/comments/hpqdur/and_that_sweet_sweet_meat/fxu5865/</permalink>
					<score>247</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>cotton961</author>
					<body>They don’t always help, I can’t remember exactly what happened since it was my first colony, but the man in black I got was nudist, brawler, and pyromaniac. 

I let the pawns kinda run themselves to see what would happen, after they were downed the man in black appears, saves them all, but... as they healed he would beat them back down until they were back in shock. After I forbade him from doctor, he simply killed the first 3 by beating them to death, and while the other two were in their bed unable to move.... he burned my whole house down with them inside. 

I got so mad I deleted the save and hopefully this monster with it, but I’m terrified he will one day reappear to exact revenge for being deleted. I’m so paranoid about it that if all my colonists are downed I just delete the save lol</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ho0wxl/it_all_started_when_kouhei_decide_to_eat_without/fxgj3ug/</permalink>
					<score>224</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Rookiebeotch</author>
					<body>I don't think you understand. The ocean wasn't named after Ivan's mistake.

Ivan made a mistake, and the consequence was the formation of a large ocean.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hniy6x/thatspretty_big/fxc7vcv/</permalink>
					<score>325</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Odd_Employer</author>
					<body>You put the right lung in, you take the right lung out, you put the right lung in and shake it all around!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hmvf66/when_your_colonists_start_eating_kibble_instead/fx8y6k6/</permalink>
					<score>318</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>AmadeusV1</author>
					<body>Alright alright hear me out. So Randy's storyteller seems to want to keep things relatively balanced. I've noticed in my ~200 hours that sometimes Randy giveth, and sometimes Randy taketh, but the two usually come in pairs. Heat wave kills a colonist, Randy blesses me with supply drops shortly after. I had a great harvest, Randy gives me flash fires. 

So, to keep things in check, could it potentially be beneficial to sacrifice a colonist every once in a while?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hm7yfz/in_theory_could_occasional_sacrifices_be/</permalink>
					<score>193</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TheCockKnight</author>
					<body>I love a good drop pod raid.  CQC action, maximum casualties = maximum drama.  Headshots, blown off pinky fingers and all of my expensive shit exploding.  Makes my dick hard until they break my fucking flatscreen.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hl4abk/drop_pod_raid/fwx66nt/</permalink>
					<score>224</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>jws_shadotak</author>
					<body>Fun tip next time you need relations with a faction and you have one of their people:

You can get higher a higher relation bonus by removing all organs from the person and sending it all back to the faction. They like the body parts more than the person.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hk8xrp/2144_hours_to_realise_that_this_was_a_thing/fwrykkf/</permalink>
					<score>411</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>the_revised_pratchet</author>
					<body>Surprisingly its all in the lips. You really need to get a good seal going otherwise you won't be able to move onto the next stage. Once your lips are firmly around the eyesocket, increase suction until you feel the eyeball move outward and towards your teeth. When you feel enough of the eyeball has passed the tips of your teeth, clamp down firmly. Congratulations, you've bitten an eyeball out!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hjnwjd/bloodlust_is_perhaps_the_best_trait_in_the_game/fwobas4/</permalink>
					<score>307</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Jelly_Noodle</author>
					<body>And no lights.

Edit: I deleted that colony because I was bored but I made a new colony which also has no tables and no lights.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hiim6c/i_have_no_tables_in_my_colony/</permalink>
					<score>156</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>MjkeSand</author>
					<body>Hey guys, is there any mod that makes pawns able to craft books so other pawns can learn their craft? Thanks in advance.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hfxws3/skillbooks_mod/</permalink>
					<score>214</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Streloki</author>
					<body>I wish you could assemble bones into a monstrosity to make a bone golem that you can animate... would be fun</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hf29o5/sometimes_i_feel_like_im_playing_rimworld_the/fvv14yf/</permalink>
					<score>263</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Spazgrim</author>
					<body>Chemical Interest / Fascination have often been considered some of the worst traits in Rimworld for a long, long time. With the changes that 1.1 brought the two have been drastically overhauled, and I think that people haven't really picked up on how the new version functions. I figured I'd write a post and try to rectify that.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

**So, what was Chemical Interest and Fascination like prior to 1.1?**

Before 1.1, Chemical Interest and Fascination had two effects, based on the severity of the trait.

* If Chemical Interest, the pawn's Character Quality would be reduced by 10%
* If Chemical Fascination, the pawn's Character Quality would be reduced by 15%
* Teetotalers get a -25 social penalty to Chemical Interest / Fascination pawns
* Both randomly have Drug Binge mental breaks just like Gourmands go on Food Binges or Pyromaniacs set things on fire. Chemical Fascination would consume many more drugs than Chemical Interest, however.

While the character quality hit was nice, the threat of losing control of your pawn at a key moment was, of course, incredibly detrimental. This was compounded by the fact that binges could be lethal if hard drugs were present in your colony, leading to occasions such an old pawn suddenly snorting yayo to death when you finally get drug production in full force, or even just getting smokeleaf / psychite / alcohol addiction and either being useless for half a year or burning through your supply on their own. This lead to the common meta of either only allowing them in colonies with no drugs (basically making them worse teetotalers, which was already a bad trait), locking up all drugs behind walls unless needed, or most commonly just turning them into a nice pair of pants and an entree.

Drug production was and is one of the biggest ways to make money, so you can imagine that for a single trait to effectively lock all that off meant that the trait was truly abysmal. To be permanently KOS was something only shared with Pyromaniacs, and at least they made bases end with a show.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

**So, what are Chemical Interest and Fascination like now?**

&amp;amp;#x200B;

With 1.1, the entirety of the trait was overhauled bar the character quality reductions, which are the same as before. Teetotaler hate is also a bit stronger.

* Drug binges are no longer specifically tied to Chemical Interest and Fascination pawns and no longer randomly occur. Instead, they are now a major mental break and can happen to any pawn if their mood is below the threshold. While my testing makes it seem like binging is more common with chemical interest / fascination pawns when they break (may just be coincidence), they get the benefit of catharsis, unlike before.
* Teetotalers get a -30 social penalty to Chemical Interest / Fascination pawns and vice versa.
* The trait causes a 'Chemical Need' bar under the pawn's Needs tab. While a pawn is awake, this bar will drain over time, and go from providing positive moodlets when filled to a more severe negative one if drugs are not taken. Chemical Interest has a +3 mood bonus devolve over time to a -6 at increments of 10%, 30%, 60%, and 75%, whereas Chemical Fascination goes from +6 to -12 at increments of 10%, 25%, 40%, 70%, and 85% chemical need. This means that Quick Sleepers burn through their chemical need at a faster rate, and Chemical Fascination pawns have a faster drain rate on top of quickly losing needs met benefits versus Chemical Interest pawns. A pawn with Chemical Fascination and Quick Sleeper burns through the bar about 9.8% faster than a pawn with only fascination, about 28.2% faster than a Chemical Interest Quick Sleeper, and around 42.8% faster than a Chemical Interest pawn alone. In effect, Chemical Interest Quick Sleepers were found to be burning through the chemical need about 11.4% faster, but if we account for sleep differences and such we can just say the trait is about a 10% difference. While sleep leads to some variance, the drain rate on the chemical need bar is approximately:

1. Chemical Fascination: 9% / day
2. Chemical Fascination+ Quick Sleeper: 9.882% (10%) / day
3. Chemical Interest: 7% / day
4. Chemical Interest + Quick Sleeper: 7.798% (8%) / day

* Drugs fill this meter back up in set increments. Both Interest and Fascination fill up the same amount for each drug, and the amount is based on whether the drug is a social drug or a hard drug. Social drugs (beer, smokeleaf joints, ambrosia, psychite tea) add 20% to the bar, whereas hard drugs (Go-juice, yayo, flake, wake-up) add 30%. Luciferium and penoxycline are medical drugs and do nothing. As a result, beer / mixing drugs is key to keeping the chemical need bar maxed out safely and consistently.
* Chemical Interest / Fascination pawns respect **Forbidden things and some restrictions.** They won't use forbidden drugs and respect limiting drug use based on mood, but may snort some yayo lying around. The only exception to this nuance is a binge mental break, but this can happen to any pawn.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

**Is it worth keeping a pawn with the traits?**

Yeah. At worst, you have a pessimist / depressive pawn with a slight decrease to raid size. At best, you have a 1/2 of / a full Optimist pawn with reduced raid size. Teetotalers are very subpar considering how powerful drugs are in all situations, so the animosity there isn't an issue. Now that they won't randomly decide to ride the Flake Train to the afterlife, the trait's actually in a pretty good spot.

All in all, the traits are pretty middle of the pack. One's easier to handle but gives less benefit in the right circumstance, the other's the opposite. The character quality / pawn value decrease on traits that aren't explicitly detrimental is basically unique and helps make up for the slightly rougher early game until you can get your first smokeleaf / psychite leaf / hops harvest (or buy some joints from a merchant).

Give good pawns with 'em a chance. They won't disappoint.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/he89t8/analysis_of_11_chemical_interest_and_fascination/</permalink>
					<score>152</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>ciel_lanila</author>
					<body>I assume so.  With my current play through I had a variant where they so gave up on the community that they became wild people.  Took a lot to get there.  

The one had their spouse die in a fire fight with a raiding group that included the colonist’s mother.  Then I didn’t  turn off the butcher humans and you can guess who was doing the butchering.  

After relocating the colony to be closer to the crashed ship I ended up getting a rescue quest for for this colonist.  They have been on, mostly, good behavior since.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hdnn9a/medical_education/fvn6yjn/</permalink>
					<score>195</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>CrimsonExploud</author>
					<body>Also some of them are only half siblings, because when I artificially impregnate prisoners for profit I use my character as the father, so the babies have good stats</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hcbla6/the_story_of_reika_story_in_comments/fvef6ad/</permalink>
					<score>260</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Greymagikk</author>
					<body>Now I can fulfill my dream of feeding my prisoners deep fried cheese and only offer them one wooden latrine in the middle of their prison. Cheers!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hbkgrp/vanilla_cooking_expanded_released_cook_with_style/fv9fx7l/</permalink>
					<score>260</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>SamtheCossack</author>
					<body>If they aren't bonded, they aren't doggos. They are self propelled meat delivery systems. Doggos are nothing like that.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hauu4e/malnutrition_and_desperation/fv56zc8/</permalink>
					<score>305</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>WhiteWolfLT</author>
					<body>Got to feed the parents to the kids, its tradition</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/h9yogc/well_fuck/fuzouam/</permalink>
					<score>243</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>RadioMelon</author>
					<body>Somehow one of my doctors managed to break her wooden leg.. and cause her physical pain.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/h8lphh/somehow_one_of_my_doctors_managed_to_break_her/</permalink>
					<score>272</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TomBergerocker</author>
					<body>I don't care if you're white, Black
Red or Blue.
If you have a working Liver;
I'm coming for you.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/h7ooh0/remember_kids/</permalink>
					<score>407</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Demonmercer</author>
					<body>So I built an oven on a steam ~~vent~~ geyser where all my "volatile" prisoners go but every time I try to assign a prisoner it says "no un-reachable, un-enclosed and marked bed available with safe temperatures" my oven has a door and roof too so is there a way to mod this out or something? thanks for the help!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/h0u1ec/why_cant_i_bake_my_prisoners/</permalink>
					<score>260</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Odd_Employer</author>
					<body>"you like this dress? It's made entirely out of scrotums; it reacts to temperature."

-Brad, probably.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gz0vw4/this_is_the_reason_why_you_should_explore/ftfcam3/</permalink>
					<score>326</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Matthias987</author>
					<body />
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gvt3lf/how_do_i_get_animals_into_shuttles/</permalink>
					<score>339</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Deadmanwater</author>
					<body>I never noticed the "Prisoner released" mood buff before, is this new?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gv5vwm/i_never_noticed_the_prisoner_released_mood_buff/</permalink>
					<score>192</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>thecrazyfrog</author>
					<body>I Just Sold 76 People Into Slavery Because I Have Nothing Better To Do With My Life</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/guqmmp/i_just_sold_76_people_into_slavery_because_i_have/</permalink>
					<score>371</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>de_kriskard</author>
					<body>I just yoink genitals from animals instead</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gp43p5/forbidden_mod/frjwhx0/</permalink>
					<score>201</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Accurina</author>
					<body>I love all animals, bison, megasloths, elephants. Especially thrumbos! They give lots of meat for our lavish meals!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/goibm0/animals_hunting_colonists/frfyclz/</permalink>
					<score>199</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>rlagusrlagus</author>
					<body>"So can we kill and eat the babies? I want to have a colony survive entirely on slave babies. Hell, id even sell a few for some nicer clothes."</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/gmfqiu/so_can_we_kill_and_eat_the_babies_i_want_to_have/</permalink>
					<score>374</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Pan_Zurkon</author>
					<body>using this method made me think something that would fit really nicely onto r/ShitRimworldSays, "wait, have I already burned the corpses after the last tribal attack?"</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gdcb43/thoughts_on_explosives/fqinsor/</permalink>
					<score>161</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>crazyabe111</author>
					<body>I Just LOVE the way my clothes Smile while they keep me from burning to death like the guy they are made from.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gif86f/cooling_properties_of_rimworld_clothing/fqezs96/</permalink>
					<score>243</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Avder42</author>
					<body>That sinking feeling when you shocklance a 17 year old Sanguine/Fast Learner and see him on fire, and then the elation of discovering you've just created a future supercrafter by way of him becoming a Trauma Savant.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gh45ed/that_sinking_feeling_when_you_shocklance_a_17/</permalink>
					<score>361</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Mostly_Harmless18101</author>
					<body>Dinning Room</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ggg6mx/dinning_room/</permalink>
					<score>153</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>vegardrichter</author>
					<body>Will not become my new colonist. im desperate, but not that desperate</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gelsdb/will_not_become_my_new_colonist_im_desperate_but/</permalink>
					<score>219</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Jummy_Dean</author>
					<body>I love children and pregnancy because I can give late abortions with a bolt action rifle.</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/ge6tke/i_love_children_and_pregnancy_because_i_can_give/</permalink>
					<score>267</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>girlinthetreetops</author>
					<body>You are very welcome, have fun with it. Send some screenshots when your first human harvest is ready!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/gbigdv/i_underestimated_how_many_people_grows_on_a_human/fp62k4h/</permalink>
					<score>203</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>SomeGuyOfTheWeb</author>
					<body>

[View Poll](https://www.reddit.com/poll/g7tfnw)</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/g7tfnw/the_most_viable_weapon_for_hunting_squirrels_is/</permalink>
					<score>307</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>WyvernVanguard</author>
					<body>Dude personally I’d fuck a megaspider before i took a kid’s kidney</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/etfp5m/nice_try_randy/ffgxusb/</permalink>
					<score>265</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Nerdcuddles</author>
					<body>One of my colonists insulted my super-soldier living weapon colonist's origin then a social fight happened</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/g6gg5d/one_of_my_colonists_insulted_my_supersoldier/</permalink>
					<score>338</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Xenophic99</author>
					<body>Furries have fur everywhere. Cat-girls have skin on most of their body. As a veteran of /r/rimworld, i assure you the difference is significant. Especially for hat-making</body>
					<permalink>/r/dankmemes/comments/g4iu08/no_need_to_worry/fnxxk0t/</permalink>
					<score>472</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>lunaticneko</author>
					<body>[Is it possible to] farm trauma savants?</body>
					<permalink>/r/ShitRimworldSays/comments/g1l803/is_it_possible_to_farm_trauma_savants/</permalink>
					<score>188</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>SolarAU</author>
					<body>In my latest colony I built a "movie theatre" for my pawns, complete with megascreen TV and masterwork human leather armchairs. 

Who says the rimworld has to be harsh and cruel?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fubwgr/my_prime_collection_of_masterwork_golden_stools/fmc5wlb/</permalink>
					<score>270</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Filican</author>
					<body>One time I had a pawn who would always puke right before eating her meal, this meant she was in an endless cycle of puking trying to eat her meal only to puke again she was literally starving the entire day and couldn’t move a single tile without puking</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ftheuw/nutrient_paste_for_the_win/fm75lsm/</permalink>
					<score>238</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Huangas</author>
					<body>Well if he’s not alive to tell the tale, then technically it’s not, or just execute him later</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fsry6r/is_it_a_warcrime/fm34ha8/</permalink>
					<score>173</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>FFFF000006</author>
					<body>It's very profitable. I once butchered a 14 y/o tribal girl for organs, and I feel great.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fp9kev/its_very_profitable_i_once_butchered_a_14_yo/</permalink>
					<score>301</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Lucius-Halthier</author>
					<body>Two years go by of prosperity and no raids go by*

Me: WHATEVER YOUR PLANNING JUST DO IT I NEED MORE CORPSES</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fi9dby/im_playing_with_randy_hes_been_real_quiet_no/fkgib4x/</permalink>
					<score>153</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Edward_Boss</author>
					<body>I found this gem on Rimworld The Corn Experience</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fg790b/i_found_this_gem_on_rimworld_the_corn_experience/</permalink>
					<score>253</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>conkikhon</author>
					<body>I love how quickly the community weaponize new features.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/f8c2b5/the_new_11_pillars_make_good_roof_traps/filw9kp/</permalink>
					<score>171</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>jhoncenu68</author>
					<body>What my colonists see as the perfect base.</body>
					<permalink>/r/SpaceCannibalism/comments/f0ec3t/what_my_colonists_see_as_the_perfect_base/</permalink>
					<score>163</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>dongusschlongus</author>
					<body>"I got so cold my pussy fell off"</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ewq3ya/i_got_so_cold_my_pussy_fell_off/</permalink>
					<score>205</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>qwertyuiop4000</author>
					<body>True, but his organs can lead to the success of a colony</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ev8ppv/can_i_harvest_peoples_organs_and_sell_them/ffuv68g/</permalink>
					<score>237</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>BilgePoster</author>
					<body>you fool, lock the pawn in there and it becomes a part of the machine. schroedingers cat doesn't account for cat based slavery.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ev8rj5/a_perpetual_energy_machine_is_physically_impos_me/ffuasu0/</permalink>
					<score>267</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Bug-in-the-Grass</author>
					<body>How many war crimes can one commit  before the kids wake up

Edit : thanks for the 450 upvotes</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/eu617w/wife_is_away_for_work_just_put_the_kids_to_sleep/fflyuya/</permalink>
					<score>169</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Spar-kie</author>
					<body>I'm cool with child slavery, organ harvesting, child organ harvesting, 
and war crimes, but I draw the line in the sand at fucking a megaspider</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/etfp5m/nice_try_randy/ffgwixy/</permalink>
					<score>210</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>USS-Iowa</author>
					<body>No -10 means they’re getting a -10 mood debuff from BEING milked</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/er9ijh/my_former_humans_sapience_is_hanging_by_a_damn/ff2m12q/</permalink>
					<score>187</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Star_verse</author>
					<body>How many war crimes has your youngest committed?! Mines gotten up to ten a week.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/emg846/_/fdoi3yv/</permalink>
					<score>255</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>tpersona</author>
					<body>Before this mod I didn't have many reasons to keep prisoners. Yeah, their organs are quiet profitable but the debuffs are a bit too much and that gets in the way of my cocain and weed production. But with Prison Labor, I can actually profit from prisoners without any downsides! I made a freezer for their dead comrades inside the prison, I put a few butcher tables in the prison and made them butcher their dead friends. I set their diet to only human meat so I save a lot of food (Paste is good too but I need my drug production at its 100% so I don't want to waste any time hauling food into the hopper). I get free human skin without any debuffs for my colonists and some extra pieces of human meat for my cannibal! I also put stone cutting tables inside the prison as well, ain't nobody wants their colonists wasting time on stones! Sometimes the prisoners can't take all of this so they tend to throw tantrums and go berserk. No big deal since I can just cut 1 of their leg and turn the other into a peg. Makes things much more manageable! But of course, their food run out eventually so I got to release them afterall. I like to keep my colonists happy so meh. At the end of the day, with minimum efforts, I basically got hundreds of stones, human leather and human meat for free. The best thing is since they all have a peg leg when I released them, even if they are to raid me again, I would have no trouble handling them. Must have mod now in my playthrough, definitely recommended!</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ej4cql/prison_labor_mod_is_awsome/</permalink>
					<score>197</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>[deleted]</author>
					<body>yeah i like to invade bases,I just take the female pawns and kill the male ones,Like vikings did,But i do it with robots.

With Rimjobworld and simple slavery you can force your slaves and prisioners to become prostitutes and earn a steady amount of silver with visitors,tenants,traders and guests.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/eicw83/does_anyone_actually_attack_faction_bases/fcp27j0/</permalink>
					<score>336</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>SmamelessMe</author>
					<body>The only psychologically unstable colonists I ever choose to recruit are now hats, so I'm good on that part.

I feel deeply for people forced by the hand of destiny to raise their weapons against my people. But at the same time, their soul-less bodies are nothing but resource to me.

As for those I capture and tend to. Well, let's just say sometimes the best a pawn can do for the good of humanity is provide their organs. I take care of that part.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorldPorn/comments/ehev41/waving_goodbye_to_rebirth_after_10_years_1181/fcl6n22/</permalink>
					<score>208</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>shoshonesamurai</author>
					<body>What age can the kids safely handle the charge rifle?(children/pregnancy mod)</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ehbgqw/what_age_can_the_kids_safely_handle_the_charge/</permalink>
					<score>186</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>sloppyfondler</author>
					<body>Sometimes the game produces great stories like this, other times you get a cannibal sensually whispering to a llama about capitalism in an effort to tame it.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ee30o5/over_3_years_since_twiddles_death_gideon_has/fbrgi98/</permalink>
					<score>356</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>reformtoxicfinal</author>
					<body>The turret keeps them honest.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/edv9yd/i_treat_my_prisoners_like_real_people/fblflb9/</permalink>
					<score>213</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TBDMS</author>
					<body>Yeah Im using babies and children for the first time and I realized I needed to change the babies drug policies because they all quickly became raging alcoholics. There's a lot of trial and will to this mood I feel like and I'm still not sure if it's working like its supposed to.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ecrci5/imagine_being_a_mother_in_rimworld/fbe09gu/</permalink>
					<score>296</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>snp4</author>
					<body>Firstly I never agreed with this fad in the first place. Cannibalising or making leather boots or war crimes on prisoners isn't exactly beneficial. Firstly, you get all the associated rebuffs and secondly, you miss out on potential recruits, therefore potential growth of the colony. I don't get the appeal in adding peg legs to prisoners which you'd otherwise recruit anyway. Human leather sucks compared to most leathers anyway, and human meat is pointless to eat when you can otherwise hunt, forage or just farm enough crops to feed your colony for years.

Sure I might chuckle at the first joke about war crimes from 2 years ago, but constant reskinned reposts just lose their appeal and become dead and overused.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/eb0owz/unpopular_opinion_the_fleshcannibalhuman_skin_fad/</permalink>
					<score>237</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TynanSylvester</author>
					<body>I just looked this up for amusement's sake. Turns out it's actually because of a bugfix.

We set it up so people who have no legs won't get 'naked' thoughts from not wearing pants. It checks if any of the pawn's not-missing body parts are in the BodyPartGroupDef called Legs. If not, it thinks the pawn has no legs, so it sets 'hasPants' to true since the check isn't needed.

Animal bodies don't have BodyPartGroupDefs configured because they're only used for apparel. Thus the check for not-missing body parts in the Legs BodyPartGroup always returns false.

So the reason animals always think they have pants is because they always think they have no legs.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/e9wyyc/an_interesting_discovery_about_animals_and_pants/fammavc/</permalink>
					<score>191</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>kisloemaslo</author>
					<body>Why my colonists can't eat my dead kids? I do not have food,and they can eat only other dead men but  ot their kids. Why?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/e6wic2/i_need_your_help/</permalink>
					<score>273</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Pausbrak</author>
					<body>Drugs are probably the easiest solution in an emergency.  A snort of yayo can clear up a huge mood debuff as long as the high lasts.  To handle it in the long term, you'll need to invest in impressive dining rooms, rec rooms, and bedrooms.  Or just go all the way and start up a drug and organ harvestijg operation.  You'll need a steady supply of kidneys to replace the ones that'll inevitably get damaged from constant drug use.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dv71mq/typical_tuesday_tutorial_thread_november_12_2019/f7iajkh/</permalink>
					<score>287</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Konstantin_J</author>
					<body>In my last colony I was trying that mod about kids and it was fun at the begining but then at some point it started to be to much kids and I was tired of them crying so I put all the kids in the cribs on a room with stone walls and burn them all with a molotov and then I realise thats probably the worst I have done on the game after nearly a 1000 hours, there was still room for improvement.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dt49y5/there_is_always_something_new_on_this_game/</permalink>
					<score>277</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TheCovenant</author>
					<body>Use animal logic too. 
Bonus points for laying the corridor with corpses. 
Keep some rats constantly breeding in a room while the disposable ones patrol a corridor or tight room. Probably a tight room. 

Some skaven shit right there.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dpln45/has_anyone_made_a_rat_chamber_that_eats_raiders/</permalink>
					<score>230</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>lunaticneko</author>
					<body>Thanks, now I'm thinking about skinning someone alive and keep them alive while I make a jacket and a hat just for them.

"See, I only want to do good things for you, so I made this shirt for you."

"YOU MOTHERF-"

(Bashes jaw of the prisoner, pulls restraints) "Be grateful. This is made just for you. Actually, it's been yours all along." (shows the tattoo side of the jacket)

(muffled screams as the prisoner is gagged)

"I'll even help you put it on!"

(muffled screams fade away)

"Oh dear. You're so happy you passed out? I'm so glad you like my work~♥"</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dmnd61/im_proud/f548m45/</permalink>
					<score>178</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>captainosome101</author>
					<body>I had a 2 year old addicted to yayo run wild which I forgot to handle because a massive black insect hive was attacking the colony. I assume he died. We never found the body and his parents are both miserable.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dj6wqa/so_this_happened/f42lrdp/</permalink>
					<score>320</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>florvas</author>
					<body>My main colonist's mother was vital to the colony - doctor and main chef. Thanks to the hospitality mod, she got engaged to a visiting tribal leader. Now me, not knowing if the marriage would mean he comes or she leaves, did the only thing a sane person in my situation could do: I had her murder him in bed with an LMG, and kept his body in the corner. 

Unfortunately, this did not go over well with her; there were many mental breaks, and after a particularly damaging raid - after which only my main colonist, his mother, and his now-legless (but with one peg) lover remained, thanks to her being in prison for rampant firestarting - he took a flamethrower and torched the place. 

Dog lived though, which was nice.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/dj1lcu/most_messed_up_thing_you_have_ever_done_in/f40p1xf/</permalink>
					<score>175</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>NotABotCom</author>
					<body>Sometimes I wish RimWorld had kenshi like arm and leg dismemberment. I just wanna see a pawns limb get YEETED across the map from being shot by a uranium slug turret.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hvhzrp/a_rimworld_colonist/fyu7oot/</permalink>
					<score>187</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>dave2293</author>
					<body>Everything was going great. The external temperature was down to about 40c, the crops were coming in, and the barns were full. One last task before bed: have Hack butcher the extra corpses in the freezer. Even if the reserve freezer's power goes out (again), I want that leather.


Right before he finishes, I get a notification: Rhino Revenge. My tamer (skill 19) pissed off the rhino and got laid out. Her guard animals put up a good fight, and when she passed out, they went back to their barn to rest. My colonists start trying to recover poor Leyton.


Fast forward 5 mins. There are now 4 downed colonists and a nudist with a poor machine pistol standing over a dead rhino in the house. I start looking to see if she can actually stabilize anyone... and the explosions start.


Two of the injured guard animals were boomalopes. Since it was late evening when they bled out, all the other boomalopes were in the boomalope barn with them. The horses keep "rescuing" the injured, burning survivors by dragging them back into the barn.


Boom. Everything runs burning into the fields. Fires on animal goes out. Animal goes back into the barn. Boom.


In 10mins, I went from a stable colony in the badlands whose worst problem was the freezer being full to a nudist crafter standing in a bloodstained hall while the herds exploded all over the crops. 2020.


PS: I would like to report that the stone barn, built to keep the heat down so the boomalopes wouldn't get heatstroke, did survive the chained explosions. Strong recommend, lol.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hv5tdg/so_last_night_2020_hit_hard/</permalink>
					<score>217</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>ripmorld</author>
					<body>I harvest their spine and give it back when they join.
It is much more space efficient</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hv45sm/unpopular_style/fyr0u1c/</permalink>
					<score>215</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>ZehAngrySwede</author>
					<body>One death is a tragedy, one million deaths is a profit.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/huiqpv/could_i_interest_you_in_a_human_leather_chair/fypj27p/</permalink>
					<score>150</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>DrManton</author>
					<body>I wonder, if you butcher a bunch of merchants, make dusters out of their leather and gift them back to the faction - is the balance positive or negative?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/huiqpv/could_i_interest_you_in_a_human_leather_chair/fynayue/</permalink>
					<score>239</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Pyros51</author>
					<body>Goes to bed with his wife.

The next morning she wakes up to find a 300kg megaspider under the covers with her...</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/htwifn/meet_adele_my_newest_recruit_who_apparently_had_a/fyjtb86/</permalink>
					<score>199</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>SparlingFam1</author>
					<body>I pay for everything in corn and body parts.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/htorvx/creditdebt_or_yayo/fyi5fbm/</permalink>
					<score>151</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>arkman575</author>
					<body>... I’m fine with turning my disobedient colonists into living carpets and treating raider camps as necro-marts, but dude...you got issues.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/ht8ymp/one_of_my_wargs_just_did_this_to_a_tortoise/fyfqvqb/</permalink>
					<score>257</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>blackiconwhitesumo</author>
					<body>Whiny bitches dont even wanna wear bloodstained clothing. I don’t want to listen to what they have to say about a cumstained power suit.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/fwx09g/after_a_17year_hyperspace_journey_i_noticed_this/fmrpcdh/</permalink>
					<score>150</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>DaddySpongeBoi</author>
					<body>Don't worry, they also get their funding from prisoners who 'mysteriously' became organless popsicle people (1 peg leg).</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hx1qe1/hol_up/fz39dvy/</permalink>
					<score>155</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>ArkhielModding</author>
					<body>BTW, is there a mod allowing you to rip the face of a prisonner and wear it (with a mood when he sees it) ?</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hxd104/when_a_person_says_they_dont_want_to_wear_a_face/fz67qt2/</permalink>
					<score>205</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Fredex8</author>
					<body>Given my penchant for performing unnecessary surgery on prisoners I'd be tempted to give a dozen prisoners peg legs and then upgrade the most beserk break prone prisoner to be fully bionic and keep them all in a small dark cell with only human meat for sustenance. I wonder how long the others would last before getting robot-ed to death.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/8upy2l/archotech_legs_are_awesome/e1haxl7/</permalink>
					<score>240</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>TheRealFedral</author>
					<body>Gonna be absolute chaos. Groups with Doomsday launchers blowing up bases, harvesting organs, and disappearing into the night, leaving legless, armless, organless husks laying on the ground.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/hz03nw/onlinecity/fzfwwh8/</permalink>
					<score>185</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Theycallmetheherald</author>
					<body>Exactly, different beasts. 

Oni is about survival

Rimworld.. not so much.. it's about dying and killing and selling the lungs and left robotic eye of a raider you captured to buy more drugs for your ambrosia addicted dog.</body>
					<permalink>/r/Oxygennotincluded/comments/i12jvj/ever_played_rimworld/fzujjbe/</permalink>
					<score>197</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>Aldiirk</author>
					<body>Mindscrews can be removed with an operation. Failure can cause brain damage, though. ¯\\\_(ツ)\_/¯

I put a mindscrew and a psychic harmonizer in a prisoner in a cramped 2x2 cell set at 33C in an attempt to turn him into a sort of "beacon of agony" to project a powerful mood debuff on attacking raids. I removed his legs to prevent him from having mental breaks. However, the area of effect was only like 30 tiles, so it didn't work, and I ended up removing both brain implants (to get them back) before turning him into doctor practicve and harvesting his liver.

...maybe that's why half my colonists had chemical fascinations and did all the drugs. It was the only way to drown out the screams echoing from the cell....</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/i1z8uh/drugs_are_underrated/g01e4q3/</permalink>
					<score>201</score>
				</li>
				<li>
					<author>EfficientSoup</author>
					<body>Send a colonist to beat up or open fire on the baby until it is unconscious and/or unable to move and you should be able to feed him afterwards since it will be unable to move and get out of his crib. Bonus melee/shooting and medical skill.</body>
					<permalink>/r/RimWorld/comments/i2e1zn/this_baby_is_throwing_himself_out_of_the_crib/g04oe2w/</permalink>
					<score>161</score>
				</li>
			</quotes>
		</database>
	</ModSettings>
</SettingsBlock>